<control_panel>
    <group title="General Info">
        <button text="Intro">
            <markdown>
                # Introduction
                ---
                Instead of choosing a class and various skills or abilities, in *Traveller* you start off as a bright-eyed 18 year old with the whole universe at your feet. You will then decide what kind of career you might want to pursue and then watch as your Traveller’s life unfolds – very possibly in a completely different direction!
                When you have finished this process, you will be ready for play with a Traveller who has history and a full career (successful or otherwise) behind them. They will now be ready for the next phase of their life, one full of excitement and adventure…
                It should be noted that there are no ‘super’ characters in *Traveller*. This game is very much based around the idea of putting ordinary people in extraordinary situations and of playing with the cards that the universe has dealt you. Be ready to make the best of what you get – much like real life (although real life tends to lack starships, exploding suns and eight foot tall intelligent lion-like aliens).
                So, another Traveller may end up as a battle-hardened marine who can shoot out a fox’s eye at 100 paces with any weapon in Charted Space but your failed rock star who never managed to get anywhere in their career may well have more to contribute to the group. After all, not every problem can be solved with a gun. In fact, in *Traveller*, a gun may cause more issues than it solves.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Summary">
            <markdown>
                # Creation Summary
                ---
                A Traveller’s abilities and skills are determined by training and past experience. Traveller creation begins with rolling characteristics, six values that describe your initial physical and mental capabilities. After determining characteristics and a few background skills from adolescent life, it is time to embark on a career. Each Traveller goes through one or more four-year career terms, which grant various skills and benefits. There are risks associated with each career – serving a tour of duty in the Imperial Marines may give a Traveller a good grounding in combat and weapons use but there is always the risk of injury in battle. A term spent in a corporation is unlikely to get a Traveller injured or killed but will not usually provide skills valuable in combat.
                In addition to skills, Travellers pick up benefits such as cash, equipment or contacts from a career. However, there are limits on how many career terms a Traveller can go through – the risks of aging or injury mount up over time and some Travellers will move between two or three careers in their lives. At some point, you will decide to leave your career for a new life of adventure before your Traveller gets too old.
                While going through a career, you can establish ties between your Traveller and those of the other players, so everyone will be old friends (or rivals!) before play begins. You will also be able to pick a skills package after everyone has finished creating their Travellers, which will allow you to fill any gaps in the group’s skill range.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <subgroup title="Aliens">
            <subsubgroup title="Aslan">
                <button text="Aslan">
                    <markdown>
                        # Aslan
                        ---
                        The Aslan are the youngest of the great powers, an expansionist species of feuding clans and predatory warriors, eager to seize all the universe has to offer. Aslan are descended from four-limbed carnivorous pouncer stock, which was originally near the top of the food chain in the forests of their homeworld, Kusyu. True to their pouncer ancestry, Aslan are capable of short bursts of speed somewhat greater than that manageable by humans. They also have slightly superior hearing and night vision. Otherwise, they are one of the most human-like of all alien species, excepting, of course, the Vargr (who are, after all, genetically-altered mammalian stock originally from Earth).
                        Early Terran explorers regarded the Aslan as ‘lionlike’ and the simile has stuck ever since, although the Aslan bear only a passing resemblance to terrestrial lions. Nonetheless, this early misnomer has influenced a great deal of human thinking about the Aslan, including terminology (the use of pride to translate ahriy, for instance) and ascribed behaviour – which is not at all leonine.
                    </markdown>
                </button>
                <button text="Characteristics">
                    <markdown>
                        # Characteristics
                        ---
                        Aslan Travellers have the following modifiers applied to their characteristics: STR+2, DEX-2.
                    </markdown>
                </button>
                <button text="Traits">
                    <markdown>
                        # Traits
                        ---
                        Aslan Travellers all possess the following traits:
                        **Dewclaw:** All Aslan have a dewclaw, which can be extended to make for a vicious close combat weapon. The dewclaw uses the Melee (natural) skill and does 1D+2 damage.
                        **Heightened Senses:** Aslan have better night vision, hearing and sense of smell than humans. All Aslan receive DM+1 to any Recon and Survival checks they have to make.
                    </markdown>
                </button>
            </subsubgroup>
            <subsubgroup title="Vargr">
                <button text="Vargr">
                    <markdown>
                        # Vargr
                        ---
                        The Vargr are the only Major Race to have been uplifted by the Ancients, a fact that the Vargr are extremely proud of. They are typically seen by other species as aggressive pirates and scavengers but the Vargr actually have a diverse culture that is deeply rooted in their pack mentality and the desire for companionship, charisma and loyalty. Their constant struggle for charisma and leadership results in a culture fuelled by conflict and change.
                        The Vargr are descended from carnivore/chaser stock; genetically engineered by the Ancients circa -300,000 from the genus Canis. The carnivores were transplanted from Terra to Lair/Grnouf in the Provence sector. The Vargr bear a close resemblance to their canine ancestry, as can be seen by their muzzle, tail and fur, although several anatomical modifications were made by the Ancients to the canine body structure. Vargr adopt a digitigrade stance (putting their weight on their toes rather than the soles of their feet) and many have a slight stoop.
                    </markdown>
                </button>
                <button text="Characteristics">
                    <markdown>
                        # Characteristics
                        ---
                        Vargr Travellers have the following modifiers applied to their characteristics: STR-1, DEX+1, END-1.
                    </markdown>
                </button>
                <button text="Traits">
                    <markdown>
                        # Traits
                        ---
                        Vargr Travellers all possess the following traits:
                        **Bite:** All Vargr possess pronounced canines, which make for a nasty close combat weapon. This bite uses the Melee (natural) skill and does 1D+1 damage.
                        **Heightened Senses:** Vargr have better hearing and sense of smell than humans. All Vargr receive DM+1 to any Recon and Survival checks they have to make. However, their eyesight is worse in darkness and they suffer DM-1 to any skill check requiring sight in dark conditions.
                    </markdown>
                </button>
            </subsubgroup>
        </subgroup>
        <button text="Characteristics">
            <markdown>
                # Characteristics
                ---
                Every person in *Traveller*, human and alien, has several characteristics that describe their base mental and physical potential. The basic characteristics for humans are shown here.
                ---
                ### Physical Characteristics
                - **Strength (STR):** A  Traveller's physical strength, fitness and forcefulness.
                - **Dexterity (DEX):** Physical co-ordination and agility, reflexes.
                - **Endurance (END):** A Traveller's stamia, determination and ability to sustain damage.
                ### Mental Characteristics
                - **Intellect (INT):** A Traveller's intelligence and quickness of mind.
                - **Education (EDU):** A m easure of a Traveller's learning and experience.
                - **Social Standing (SOC):** A Traveller's place in society.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Rolling Characteristics">
            <markdown>
                # Rolling Characteristics
                ---
                To determine your Traveller’s characteristics, roll 2D one after another and assign the scores in any order you wish to the six characteristics, starting with STR. Record them on your character sheet.
                Alternatively, you may wish instead to assign each score to the characteristics in order, starting with STR, then DEX, then END and so on. After all, we do not get to decide how strong or smart we are before we are born!
                For each characteristic, determine its Dice Modifier (DM) on the Characteristic Modifiers table.
                | Characteristic Score | Dice Modifier |
                | --- | --- |
                | 0 | -3 |
                | 1-2 | -2 |
                | 3-5 | -1 |
                | 6-8 | +0 |
                | 9-11 | +1 |
                | 12-14 | +2 |
                | 15+ | +3 |
                As you progress through your career, you may find your characteristics change.
                The maximum score for a characteristic is 15 for an unaugmented Traveller. There are exceptions to this but they will be covered later for specific rules and circumstances.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Skills">
            <markdown>
                # Skills
                ---
                Skills are the most important aspect of a Traveller. A Traveller’s proficiency in any skill is denoted by their level in that skill.
                ---
                ### Background Skills
                ---
                Before embarking on your careers, you receive a number of background skills equal to your EDU DM +3 (so, 0 to 6, depending on your EDU score), chosen from the list here. This represents the knowledge you have picked up during adolescence and will allow you to function at a basic level in a technological society.
                | | | |
                | --- | --- | --- |
                | Admin 0 | Electronics 0 | Science 0 |
                | Animals 0 | Flyer 0 | Seafarer 0 |
                | Art 0 | Language 0 | Streetwise 0 |
                | Athletics 0 | Mechanic 0 | Survival 0 |
                | Carouse 0 | Medic 0 | Vacc Suit 0 |
                | Drive 0 | Profession 0 | |
                At this point, you are 18 years old and ready to take on the universe!
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Life Events">
            <markdown>
                | 2D | Event |
                | --- | --- |
                | 2 | **Sickness or Injury:** You are injured or become sick. Roll on the Injury table. |
                | 3 | **Birth or Death:** Someone close to you dies, like a friend or family member. Alternatively, someone close to you gives birth (or is born!). You are involved in some fashion (father or mother, relative, godparent and so forth). |
                | 4 | **Ending of Relationship:** A romantic relationship involving you ends. Badly. Gain a Rival or Enemy. |
                | 5 | **Improved Relationship:** A romantic relationship involving you deepens, possibly leading to marriage or some other emotional commitment. Gain an Ally. |
                | 6 | **New Relationship:** You become involved in a romantic relationship. Gain an Ally. |
                | 7 | **New Contact:** You gain a new Contact. |
                | 8 | **Betrayal:** You are betrayed in some fashion by a friend. If you have any Contacts or Allies, convert one into a Rival or Enemy. Otherwise, gain a Rival or an Enemy. |
                | 9 | **Travel:** You move to another world. You gain DM+2 to your next qualification roll. |
                | 10 | **Good Fortune:** Something good happens to you; you come into money unexpectedly, have a lifelong dream come true, get a book published or have some other stroke of good fortune. Gain DM+2 to any one Benefit roll. |
                | 11 | **Crime:** You commit or are the victim (or are accused) of a crime. Lose one Benefit roll or take the Prisoner career in your next term. |
                | 12 | **Unusual Event:** Something weird happens. Roll 1D (see below table) |
                ---
                | 1D | Unusual Event |
                | --- | --- |
                | 1 | **Psionics:** You encounter a Psionic institute. You may immediately test your Psionic Strength and, if you qualify, take the Psion career in your next term. |
                | 2 | **Aliens:** You spend time among an alien species. Gain Science 1 and a Contact among an alien species. |
                | 3 | **Alien Artefact:** You have a strange and unusual device from an alien culture that is not normally available to humans. |
                | 4 | **Amnesia:** Something happened to you but you do not know what it was. |
                | 5 | **Contact with Government:** You briefly came into contact with the highest echelons of the Imperium – an Archduke or the Emperor, perhaps, or Imperial intelligence. |
                | 6 | **Ancient Technology:** You have something older than the Imperium or even something older than humanity. |
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Benefits">
            <markdown>
                # Benefits
                ---
                In the course of a Traveller’s career, they may manage to save some money. They may also acquire equipment and other benefits from their previous employers – a Scout might be mustered out of the service with a reserve Scout Ship, for example, or a Marine might get to keep their combat armour and so on. These are determined by Benefit rolls.
                Benefits are gained when a Traveller leaves a career. A Traveller gets one Benefit roll for every full term served in that career. You also get extra Benefit rolls if you reached a high rank.
                There are two columns for Benefit rolls in each career – the Cash column and the Other Benefits column. You may only roll on the Cash column a maximum of three times across all your careers.
                ---
                ### Benefits of Rank
                | Highest Rank Reached | Bonus Benefit Rolls |
                | --- | --- |
                | 1-2 | 1 |
                | 3-4 | 2 |
                | 5-6 | 3, and DM+1 to all Benefit rolls from this career |
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Cash Benefits">
            <markdown>
                # Cash Benefits
                ---
                A Traveller with the Gambler skill gains DM+1 to all rolls on Cash columns.
                If the Traveller has any money left, they may purchase personal equipment worth up to Cr10000 before they start adventuring. More expensive items can be bought in play but Travellers will have to seek them out. Any left-over money can be converted into cash, trade goods or just saved.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <subgroup title="Other Benefits">
            <button text="Armour">
                <markdown>
                    # Armour
                    ---
                    Select any type of armour with a limit of Cr10000 and TL12. If you roll this Benefit again, then you can either select another type of armour with the same limits or trade your original in for armour with a limit of Cr25000.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Blade">
                <markdown>
                    # Blade
                    ---
                    Select any blade weapon with a limit of Cr1000 and TL12. If you roll this Benefit again, you may take another blade or one level in the Melee (blade) skill.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Characteristic Increase">
                <markdown>
                    # Characteristic Increase
                    ---
                    Increase the listed characteristic by the amount shown, up to your racial maximum. Human characters are limited to a score of 15. Characteristic increases above 15 are lost, with the exception of SOC increases – every point of excess SOC becomes a Ship Share.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Cybernetic Implant">
                <markdown>
                    # Cybernetic Implant
                    ---
                    Gain any augmentations (see page 106) with a limit of Cr75000 and TL12. If you roll this Benefit again, then you may either take a different augmentation or increase the one you already possess by one level of Improvement (this may take it above the Credit and TL limit).
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Free Trader">
                <markdown>
                    # Free Trader
                    ---
                    You receive a free trader with 25% of the mortgage paid off on it. Roll 1D times on the Spacecraft Quirks table. If you roll this Benefit again, an additional 25% of the mortgage has been paid off – if you roll this Benefit four times, the free trader will have no mortgage and it will be all yours! Alternatively, you may select a far trader instead.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Gun">
                <markdown>
                    # Gun
                    ---
                    Select any common or military ranged weapon with a limit of Cr3000 and TL12. If you roll this benefit again, you may take another weapon or one level in the appropriate Gun Combat skill for a weapon already received as a Benefit.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Lab Ship">
                <markdown>
                    # Lab Ship
                    ---
                    You receive a lab ship with 25% of the mortgage paid off on it. Roll 1D times on the Spacecraft Quirks table. If you roll this Benefit again, an additional 25% of the mortgage has been paid off – if you roll this Benefit four times, the lab ship will have no mortgage and it will be all yours!
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Personal Vehicle">
                <markdown>
                    # Personal Vehicle
                    ---
                    You receive a personal vehicle, such as a ground car or air/raft. You can choose exactly what type of vehicle this is but it may not be armed and has a limit of Cr300000 and TL10. If you roll this Benefit again, gain a level of Drive or Flyer.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Scientific Equipment">
                <markdown>
                    # Scientific Equipment
                    ---
                    Gain any one piece of scientific equipment with a limit of Cr2000 and TL12. If you roll this Benefit again, take another piece of scientific equipment or gain one level in Electronics or Science.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Scout Ship">
                <markdown>
                    # Scout Ship
                    ---
                    You receive a scout ship. You have full use of the ship and can modify it as you see fit but it still belongs to the Scout Service and can (and will!) be recalled back into service as needed. This means you will be expected to complete missions for the Scout Service from time-to-time. If you roll this Benefit more than once, re-roll the result.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ship's Boat">
                <markdown>
                    # Ship's Boat
                    ---
                    You receive a ship’s boat or other small craft with a limit of MCr10 and TL12. If you roll this Benefit again, gain Pilot (small craft). Alternatively, receive a Ship Share instead.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ship Shares">
                <markdown>
                    # Ship Shares
                    ---
                    You obtain one or more Ship Shares that can be put towards obtaining a ship. Each share is worth MCr1 but cannot be redeemed for cash.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Weapon">
                <markdown>
                    # Weapon
                    ---
                    Select any weapon with a limit of Cr3000 and TL12. If you roll this benefit again, you may take another weapon or one level in the appropriate Melee or Gun Combat skill for a weapon already received as a Benefit.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="TAS Membership">
                <markdown>
                    # TAS Membership
                    ---
                    You are a member of the Traveller’s Aid Society (TAS), a private organisation that maintains hostels and facilities at all Class A and B starports in many parts of human space. Facilities are available (at reasonable cost) to members and their guests. Receipt of membership in the Traveller’s Aid Society as a benefit may be construed as a reward for heroism or extraordinary service to the Society rather than an official benefit from a career. Membership is for life and not transferable.
                    Membership may also be purchased for MCr1, although it is possible for an application to be ‘black-balled’ by an existing member. The Traveller’s Aid Society is an exclusive organisation, made up of those who are truly citizens of the galaxy, not just a single world.
                    The TAS invests its membership fees and other incomes; it uses its capital and return to provide benefits to its members. Every two months, it pays dividends in the form of one high passage to each member. This passage may be used, retained or sold.
                    Membership may only be received once per Traveller. If you roll this Benefit again, receive two Ship Shares instead.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Yatch">
                <markdown>
                    # Yatch
                    ---
                    You receive a yacht with 25% of the mortgage paid off on it. Roll 1D times on the Spacecraft Quirks table. If you roll this Benefit again, an additional 25% of the mortgage has been paid off – if you roll this benefit four times, the yacht will have no mortgage and it will be all yours! Alternatively, you may select a Safari Ship instead.
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <button text="Pension">
            <markdown>
                # Pension
                ---
                A Traveller that leaves a career (other than Scout, Rogue, Prisoner or Drifter) after at least five terms is considered to have retired and receives a pension. This pension is paid at the beginning of each year, effective upon leaving the service and may be collected at any Class A or B starport.
                ---
                | Terms | Pay |
                | --- | --- |
                | 5 | Cr10,000 |
                | 6 | Cr12,000 |
                | 7 | Cr14,000 |
                | 8 | Cr16,000 |
                | 9+ | Cr2,000 per term beyond 8 |
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Ageing">
            <markdown>
                # Ageing
                ---
                The effects of ageing begin when a Traveller reaches 34 years of age (at the end of their fourth career term). At the end of the fourth term and at the end of every term thereafter, the Traveller must roll 2D on the Ageing table. Use the Traveller’s total number of terms as a negative DM on this table; the older you are, the heavier the effects of ageing will weigh upon you.
                The Traveller may choose which characteristics are affected by ageing.
                ---
                | 2D | Effects of Ageing |
                | --- | --- |
                | -6 | Reduce three physical characteristics by 2, reduce one mental characteristic by 1 |
                | -5 | Reduce three physical characteristics by 2 |
                | -4 | Reduce two physical characteristics by 2, reduce one physical characteristic by 1 |
                | -3 | Reduce one physical characteristic by 2, reduce two physical characteristic by 1 |
                | -2 | Reduce three physical characteristics by 1 |
                | -1 | Reduce two physical characteristics by 1 |
                | 0 | Reduce one physical characteristic by 1 |
                | 1+ | No effect |
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Ageing Crisis">
            <markdown>
                # Ageing Crisis
                ---
                If any characteristic is reduced to 0, then the Traveller suffers an ageing crisis. The Traveller dies unless they pay 1D x Cr10000 for medical care, which will bring any characteristics back up to 1. The Traveller automatically fails any qualification rolls from now on.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Anagathics">
            <markdown>
                # Anagathics
                ---
                At the start of any career term, a Traveller can start taking anagathics by rolling SOC 10+ (if you roll 2 exactly, you must instead go straight to the Prisoner career in this term). While using anagathic drugs, the Traveller effectively does not age – add the number of terms since the Traveller started taking anagathics as a positive DM to rolls on the Ageing table. If a Traveller stops taking anagathics for any reason in the future, then they must roll immediately on the Ageing table as the shock of their system beginning to age again strikes.
                Anagathics have two drawbacks. First, the combined risk of trying to obtain a reliable supply and the disruption to their biochemistry means the Traveller must make two Survival checks in each term instead of one. If either or both checks are failed, the Traveller suffers a Mishap.
                Second, the drugs cost 1D x Cr25000 for each term the Traveller uses the drugs. These costs are paid out of the Traveller’s eventual cash benefits. If the Traveller cannot pay these bills, they go into debt – see Medical Bills.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Injuries">
            <markdown>
                # Injuries
                ---
                Travellers wounded in combat or accidents during creation must roll on the Injury table to see how bad their injuries are.
                ---
                | 1D | Injury |
                | --- | --- |
                | 1 | Nearly killed – reduce one physical characteristic by 1D, reduce two other physical characteristics by 2. |
                | 2 | Severely injured – reduce one physical characteristic by 1D. |
                | 3 | Missing Eye or Limb – reduce STR or DEX by 2. |
                | 4 | Scarred – you are scarred and injured. Reduce any physical characteristic by 2. |
                | 5 | Injured. Reduce any physical characteristic by 1. |
                | 6 | Lightly Injured. No permanent effect. |
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Medical Care">
            <markdown>
                # Medical Care
                ---
                If you have been injured, then medical care may be able to undo the effects of the damage. Some worlds have the technology to clone or rebuild damaged organs; others specialise in transplants or cybernetic replacements. Regardless of the technique used, medical care is expensive.
                The restoration of a lost characteristic costs Cr5000 per point.
                If you were injured in the service of an organisation, then a portion of your medical care may be paid for. Roll 2D on the Medical Bills table, adding your rank as a DM.
                ---
                | Career | Roll of 4+ | Roll of 8+ | Roll of 12+ |
                | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                | Army/Navy/Marine | 75% | 100% | 100% |
                | Agent/Noble/Scholar/Entertainer/Merchant/Citizen | 50% | 75% | 100% |
                | Scout/Rogue/Drifter | 0% | 50% | 75% |
            </markdown>
        </button>
    </group>
    <group title="Pre-Career Education">
        <button text="Info">
            <markdown>
                # Pre-Career Education
                ---
                Before a Traveller embarks on a lifelong career, there are educational options that may be worth considering. These are going to university or attending a military academy.
                This usually takes place in a Traveller’s first term (in place of a career), although it can be delayed up until the third term if a term or two in a career is desired. From term four onwards, pre-career education is no longer available.
                A Traveller can select university or military academy, making a roll for successful entry. If this is failed, the Traveller must immediately attempt entry into a career and, failing that, be drafted as normal. Further attempts can be made in terms two and three if desired but only one attempt can be made for entry to one of these precareer options in any one term.
                Once successful entry has been achieved, the Traveller will gain any skills noted and roll on the Pre-career Events table. Upon successful graduation, one or more benefits will be awarded. Unlike a career, there is no mustering out or gaining of anything else other than the benefits listed. If graduation is not achieved, then no benefits are gained although the Traveller will still have earned some skills during this time.
                After successful graduation, a Traveller may attempt to enter a career of their choice as normal, although they may have earned bonuses or automatic entry to certain careers, as listed under graduation benefits.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Events">
            <markdown>
                # Events
                ---
                For any term a Traveller spends in pre-career education, roll on the Pre-career Events table. As with career events, other Travellers may be linked to with the connections rule – perhaps they even spent time in the same university or academy!
                If drafted through an event, enter the new career next term but do not graduate. This (and similar effects) can cause a Traveller to be drafted more than once.
                | 2D | Event |
                | --- | --- |
                | 2 | You are approached by an underground (and highly illegal) psionic group who sense potential in you. You may test your PSI and attempt to enter the Psion career in any subsequent term. |
                | 3 | Your time in education is not a happy one and you suffer a deep tragedy; perhaps you become hopelessly addicted to drink or drugs, a failed romance leaves you in tatters or a fatal accident involving a close friend shakes your confidence. You crash and fail to graduate. |
                | 4 | A supposedly harmless prank goes wrong and someone gets hurt, physically or emotionally. Roll SOC 8+. If you succeed, gain a Rival. If you fail, gain an Enemy. If you roll 2, you fail to graduate and must take the Prisoner career in your next term. |
                | 5 | Taking advantage of youth, you party as much as you study. Gain Carouse 1. |
                | 6 | You become involved in a tightly knit clique or group and make a pact to remain friends forever, wherever in the galaxy you may end. Gain D3 Allies. |
                | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                | 8 | You join a political movement. Roll SOC 8+. If successful, you become a leading figure. Gain one Ally within the movement but gain one Enemy in wider society. |
                | 9 | You develop a healthy interest in a hobby or other area of study. Gain any skill of your choice, with the exception of Jack-of-all-Trades, at level 0. |
                | 10 | A newly arrived tutor rubs you up the wrong way and you work hard to overturn their conclusions. Roll 9+ on any skill you have learned during this term. If successful, you provide a truly elegant proof that soon becomes accepted as the standard approach. Gain a level in the skill you rolled on and the tutor as a Rival. |
                | 11 | War comes and a wide-ranging draft is instigated. You can either flee and join the Drifter career next term or be drafted (roll 1D: 1–3 Army, 4–5 Marine, 6 Navy). Either way, you do not graduate this term. However, if you roll SOC 9+, you can get enough strings pulled to avoid the draft and complete your education – you may attempt graduation normally and are not drafted. |
                | 12 | You gain wide-ranging recognition of your initiative and innovative approach to study. Increase your SOC by +1. |
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <subgroup title="University">
            <button text="Entry">
                <markdown>
                    # University
                    ---
                    Many worlds have one or more universities within their major settlements but even citizens of the most remote system can engage in university education through the use of computer networks and interstellar communications. A university education will channel a Traveller’s efforts into a narrow range of skills but there are few other ways to become more skilful within them so quickly.
                    **Entry:** EDU 6+
                    DM-1 if in Term Two, DM-2 if in Term Three
                    DM+1 if SOC 9 or higher
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skills">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills
                    ---
                    Choose a level 0 and a level 1 skill from the following:
                    | | | |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Admin | Astrogation | Medic |
                    | Advocate | Electronics (any) | Navigation |
                    | Animals (training or veterinary) | Engineer (any) | Profession (any) |
                    | Art (any) | Language (any) | Science (any) |
                    Increase EDU by +1
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Graduation">
                <markdown>
                    # Graduation
                    ---
                    **Graduation:** INT 6+. If 10+ is rolled, graduate with honours.
                    ---
                    **Graduation Benefits**
                    - Increase both of the skills chosen before by one level.
                    - Increase EDU by an additional +1.
                    - Graduation grants DM+1 (DM+2 if graduation was with honours) to qualify for the following careers; Agent, Army, Citizen (corporate), Entertainer (journalist), Marines, Navy, Scholar, Scouts.
                    -Graduation allows a commission roll to be taken before the first term of a military career, so long as it is the first career chosen after university. Success will mean the Traveller enters the career at officer rank 1. If graduation was with honours, DM+2 is granted on this first commission roll.
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Military Academy">
            <button text="Entry">
                <markdown>
                    # Military Academy
                    ---
                    For those looking to dedicate their lives to military service, there is no better option than joining an academy to round out an education. This is a popular choice for those coming from ‘military’ families or those having grown up never considering anything other than a life in uniform. A term within a military academy can set a recruit’s career for great things, so competition to gain one of the limited number of open student slots is fierce.
                    Before joining a military academy, you must decide whether it is an academy of the Army, Marines or Navy.
                    ---
                    **Entry:** Army END 7+, Marines END 8+, Navy INT 8+
                    DM-2 if in Term Two, DM-4 if in Term Three.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skills">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills
                    ---
                    Gain all Service Skills of the military career the academy is tied to at level 0, as with basic training.
                    | Army | Marines | Navy |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Drive or Vacc Suit | Athletics | Pilot |
                    | Athletics | Vacc Suit | Vacc Suit |
                    | Gun Combat | Tactics | Athletics |
                    | Recon | Heavy Weapons | Gunner |
                    | Melee | Gun Combat | Mechanic |
                    | Heavy Weapons | Stealth | Gun Combat |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Graduation">
                <markdown>
                    # Graduation
                    ---
                    **Graduation:** INT 7+. If 11+ is rolled, graduate with honours.
                    DM+1 if END 8 or higher, DM+1 if SOC 8 or higher.
                    ---
                    **Graduation Benefits**
                    - If entering the same military career the academy is tied to, select any three Service Skills and increase them to level 1.
                    - Increase EDU by +1.
                    - If the Traveller graduated with honours, increase SOC by +1 as well.
                    - Graduation allows automatic entry into the military career the academy is tied to, so long as it is the first career attempted by the Traveller after graduation.
                    - Graduation allows a commission roll to be taken before the first term of a military career, so long as it is the first career chosen after university, with DM+2. Success will mean the Traveller enters the career at officer rank 1. If graduation was with honours, the Traveller will automatically pass this roll.
                    ---
                    If a Traveller attends a military academy but fails to graduate, they may still automatically enter the military career that the academy is tied to, so long as they did not roll 2 or less on the graduation roll. If they choose to enter this career, they may not make a commission roll in the first term.
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
    </group>
    <group title="Careers">
        <subgroup title="Career Descriptions">
            <button text="Careers">
                # Careers
                ---
                Next, your Traveller engages in one or more career terms, representing their experiences and adventures before the start of the campaign. Each career term lasts for four years, even if a Traveller fails a Survival roll or is forced to leave a career.
                At many points during a career, a Traveller will have to make a dice roll of some sort. Many of these rolls are based on characteristics – simply roll 2D, add the DM from the listed characteristic and try to get a total higher than or equal to the listed value.
                So, a roll of INT 8+ means ‘roll 2D, add your Intellect DM and you succeed if you roll an 8 or more’.
                A few rolls are skill checks, where you add any levels in that skill. For example, a roll of Gun Combat 8+ would mean ‘roll 2D, add your Gun Combat skill level and get 8 or more to succeed’.
                In each career, there are three assignments, representing different aspects of the career. Pick one of these assignments when you enter the career.
            </button>
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Qualification
                    ---
                    This is what you need to roll to enter that career.
                    If you fail this check, you cannot enter your chosen career this term. You must either submit to the draft or take the Drifter career for this term. If you leave a career, you cannot return to it in the next term.
                    The draft and the Drifter career are exceptions to this rule – you can be drafted into a career you were previously in but got ejected from and the Drifter career is always open.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skills/Training">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    Each career has four or five types of skill table associated with it – Personal Development, Service Skills, Assignment Skills (divided into three sub-tables corresponding to assignments), Officer and Advanced Education. In each term you spend in a career, pick one of these tables and roll 1D to see which skill you increase.
                    You may only roll on the Advanced Education or Commissioned tables if you have the listed requirement (usually EDU 8 or higher, or a certain rank).
                    Skills can be listed with or without an associated level. If no specific level is listed, then you gain that skill at level 1 if you do not have it already, or increase its level by +1 if you are already trained in that field. If a level is listed, then you gain the skill at that level so long as it is higher than your current level in the skill.
                    For example, Gambler 0 would mean you receive the Gambler skill at level 0. This is of benefit to you only if you have no Gambler skill.
                    Vacc Suit would mean you increase your Vacc Suit skill by +1 or gain it at level 1 if you have no Vacc Suit skill to begin with. If you have Vacc Suit 0, it increases to 1, if you have Vacc Suit 2 it rises to 3 and so forth.
                    Streetwise 1 would mean you get the Streetwise skill at level 1. If your Streetwise skill is already 1 or more, then this is of no benefit to you. If you have no Streetwise skill, or it is only at 0, you jump straight to Streetwise 1.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Limits">
                <markdown>
                    # Skill Limits
                    ---
                    A skill may never be increased beyond level 4 during Traveller creation. Once a skill has reached level 4, any additional increases are lost. In addition, a Traveller may never have a total number of skill levels higher than three times their combined INT and EDU.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Basic Training">
                <markdown>
                    # Basic Training
                    ---
                    For your first career only, instead of rolling for a skill, you get all the skills listed on the Service Skills table at level 0 as your basic training. For subsequent careers, you may pick any one skill listed in the Service Skills table at level 0 as your basic training.
                    Citizens and Drifters are an exception to this. They both use their appropriate Assignment Skills for basic training.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Survival">
                <markdown>
                    # Survival
                    ---
                    Each career has a survival roll. If you fail this roll, you must immediately roll on the Mishap table for the career. This mishap will force you to leave the career immediately unless otherwise stated. You will also lose the Benefit roll for the current term. A natural 2 on the survival roll is always a failure.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    If you are still in your career after resolving the survival roll, roll on the career’s Events table to see what interesting things befall you this term.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Advancement">
                <markdown>
                    # Advancement
                    ---
                    Each career has an advancement roll to represent your successful (or otherwise) path through the career. You start each career at rank 0.
                    If you make a successful advancement roll, move to the next higher rank and gain an extra roll on any of the skill tables available for your career. You also get any bonuses listed for your new rank. You may only attempt to advance once per term.
                    If your advancement roll is equal to or less than the number of terms you have spent in this career, then you cannot continue in this career after this term. Either your services are no longer required, or events have caused you to leave, or perhaps you are simply bored and want a new challenge.
                    If you roll a natural 12, then you must continue in this career. You are too valuable to lose and will be strongarmed into staying.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Commission">
                <markdown>
                    # Commission
                    ---
                    This only applies to the military careers of Army, Navy and Marines. A Traveller who succeeds at a commission roll becomes a rank 1 officer in that career and progresses on the officer’s rank table from then on. Trying for a commission is optional.
                    You may only attempt to gain a commission in your first term unless your SOC is 9 or higher, in which case you may try for a commission in any term. However, there is DM-1 applied to commission rolls for every term after the first.
                    Some events give a bonus DM to advancement rolls or grant automatic advancement. You can apply these DMs to commission rolls also.
                    If you gain a commission, you may not roll for advancement in the same term. Travellers can still roll for advancement if they fail a commission roll.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks/Bonuses">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    You begin at rank 0 in a new career. Each time you succeed with an advancement roll, you move up to the next rank. Ranks are most important for military careers, such as the Army or Navy, but every career has its own internal hierarchies and levels of authority and responsibility. However, not all ranks have a title like the military.
                    Some ranks have bonuses associated with them, such as extra skills. These are acquired immediately upon attaining the rank.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Benefits">
                <markdown>
                    # Benefits
                    ---
                    When you leave a career for any reason, you gain material benefits from that career, representing money, equipment and influence acquired during your years of work.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Drifters/Draft">
                <markdown>
                    # Drifters and the Draft
                    ---
                    You may attempt to enlist in one career each term if you are not continuing with an existing career. If you fail to qualify for a new career, you have two options. You can either apply to the draft, and be randomly sent to one of the military services, or you may spend that term travelling as a Drifter, without true career or purpose. A Traveller may only enter the draft once in their lifetime unless otherwise stated.
                    | 1D | Career (assignment) |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Navy (any) |
                    | 2 | Army (any) |
                    | 3 | Marine (any) |
                    | 4 | Merchant (merchant marine) |
                    | 5 | Scout (any) |
                    | 6 | Agent (law enforcement) |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Changing Careers">
                <markdown>
                    # Changing Careers
                    ---
                    A Traveller may get forced out of a career due to a mishap or event, or may simply leave voluntarily to pursue a more exciting or more lucrative life elsewhere.
                    To enter a new career, a Traveller need only make the appropriate qualification roll at the start of a new term. If they fail, they must either submit to the draft (if they have not already done so earlier in life) or become a Drifter.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Changing Assignments">
                <markdown>
                    # Changing Assignments
                    ---
                    Instead of a whole new career, a Traveller may instead be interested in focussing on another aspect of their existing career by changing their assignment.
                    For assignments in the Army, Marine, Navy, Nobility, Rogue, Scholar or Scout career, this simply requires a qualification roll. If this is unsuccessful, the Traveller continues in the career with the same assignment they had before without penalty. If the qualification roll is made, the Traveller now adopts the new assignment and continues in the career, retaining their rank.
                    New assignments in the Agent, Citizen, Entertainer and Merchant careers are considered to be new careers. Upon voluntarily leaving the career (a change in assignment cannot be done if you have been ejected from the career – no one will hire you!), Benefit rolls are made as normal and a qualification roll is necessary to enter the assignment. If this is failed, the Traveller must enter the draft or become a Drifter.
                    If the attempt to change assignment is successful, the career begins afresh with the new assignment, with the Traveller starting at rank 0.
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Agent">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Agent
                    ---
                    Law enforcement agencies, corporate operatives, spies and others who work in the shadows.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** INT 6+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignments">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Law Enforcement:** You are a police officer or detective.
                    **Intelligence:** You work as a spy or saboteur.
                    **Corporate:** You work for a corporation, spying on rival organisations.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Law Enforcement | END 6+ | INT 6+ |
                    | Intelligence | INT 7+ | INT 5+ |
                    | Corporate | INT 5+ | INT 7+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr1,000 | Scientific Equipment |
                    | 2 | Cr2,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr5,000 | Ship Share |
                    | 4 | Cr7,500 | Weapon |
                    | 5 | Cr10,000 | Cybernetic Implant |
                    | 6 | Cr25,000 | SOC + 1 or Cybernetic Implant |
                    | 7 | Cr50,000 | TAS Membership |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 8) | Law Enforcement | Intelligence | Corporate |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Gun Combat | Streetwise | Advocate | Investigate | Investigate | Investigate |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Drive | Language | Recon | Recon | Electronics (computers) |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Investigate | Explosives | Streetwise | Electronics (comms) | Stealth |
                    | 4 | Melee | Flyer | Medic | Stealth | Stealth | Carouse |
                    | 5 | INT +1 | Recon | Vacc Suit | Melee | Persuade | Deception |
                    | 6 | Athletics | Gun Combat | Electronics | Advocate | Deception | Streetwise |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Law Enforcement | Skill or Bonus | Intelligence/Corporate | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | Rookie | — | — | — |
                    | 1 | Corporal | Streetwise 1 | Agent | Deception 1 |
                    | 2 | Sergeant | — | Field Agent | Investigate 1 |
                    | 3 | Detective | — | — | — |
                    | 4 | Lieutenant | Investigate 1 | Special Agent | Gun Combat 1 |
                    | 5 | Chief | Admin 1 | Assistant Director | — |
                    | 6 | Commissioner | SOC +1 | Directory | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | A criminal or other figure under investigation offers you a deal. Accept and you leave this career without further penalty (although you lose the Benefit roll as normal). Refuse and you must roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. You gain an Enemy and one level in any skill you choose. |
                    | 3 | An investigation goes critically wrong or leads to the top, ruining your career. Roll Advocate 8+. If you succeed, you may keep the Benefit roll from this term. If you roll 2, you must take the Prisoner career in your next term. |
                    | 4 | You learn something you should not know and people want to kill you for it. Gain an Enemy and Deception 1. |
                    | 5 | Your work ends up coming home with you and someone gets hurt. Choose one of your Contacts, Allies or family members and roll twice on the Injury table for them, taking the lower result. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | An investigation takes on a dangerous turn. Roll Investigate 8+ or Streetwise 8+. If you fail, roll on the Mishap table. If you succeed, increase one of these skills by one level: Deception, Jack-of-allTrades, Persuade or Tactics. |
                    | 4 | You complete a mission for your superiors and are suitably rewarded. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll from this career. |
                    | 5 | You establish a network of contacts. Gain D3 Contacts. |
                    | 6 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 8+ to increase any one skill you already have by one level. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You go undercover to investigate an enemy. Roll Deception 8+. If you succeed, roll immediately on the Rogue or Citizen Events table and make one roll on any Specialist skill table for that career. If you fail, roll immediately on the Rogue or Citizen Mishap table. |
                    | 9 | You go above and beyond the call of duty. Gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 10 | You are given specialist training in vehicles. Gain one of Drive 1, Flyer 1, Pilot 1 or Gunner 1. |
                    | 11 | You are befriended by a senior agent. Either increase Investigate by one level or DM+4 to an advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | Your efforts uncover a major conspiracy against your employers. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Army">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Army
                    ---
                    Members of the planetary armed fighting forces. Soldiers deal with planetary surface actions, battles and campaigns. Such individuals may also be mercenaries for hire.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** END 5+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                    DM-2 if you are aged 30 or more
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Support:** You are an engineer, cook or in some other role behind the front lines.
                    **Infantry:** You are one of the Poor Bloody Infantry on the ground.
                    **Cavalry:** You are one of the crew of a gunship or tank.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Support | END 5+ | EDU 7+ |
                    | Infantry | STR 6+ | EDU 6+ |
                    | Cavalry | DEX 7+ | INT 5+ |
                    ---
                    **Commission:** SOC 8+
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr2,000 | Cybernetic Implant |
                    | 2 | Cr5,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr10,000 | EDU +1 |
                    | 4 | Cr10,000 | Weapon |
                    | 5 | Cr10,000 | Armour |
                    | 6 | Cr20,000 | END +1 or Cybernetic Implant |
                    | 7 | Cr30,000 | SOC +1 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skills Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 8) | Officer (Commissioned Only) | Support | Infantry | Cavalry |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Drive or Vacc Suit | Tactics (military) | Tactics (military) | Mechanic | Gun Combat | Mechanic |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Athletics | Electronics | Leadership | Drive or Flyer | Melee | Drive |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Gun Combat | Navigation | Advocate | Profession | Heavy Weapons | Flyer |
                    | 4 | Gambler | Recon | Explosives | Diplomat | Explosives | Stealth | Recon |
                    | 5 | Medic | Melee | Engineer | Electronics | Electronics (comms) | Athletics | Heavy  Weapons (vehicle) |
                    | 6 | Melee | Heavy Weapons | Survival | Admin | Medic | Recon | Electronics (sensors) |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Enlisted | Skill or Bonus | Officer | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | Private | Gun Combat 1 | | |
                    | 1 | Lance Corporal | Recon 1 | Lieutenant | Leadership 1 |
                    | 2 | Corporal | — | Captain | — |
                    | 3 | Lance Sergeant | Leadership 1 | Major | Tactics (military) 1 |
                    | 4 | Sergeant | — | Lieutenant Colonel | — |
                    | 5 | Gunnery Sergeant | — | Colonel | — |
                    | 6 | Sergeant Major | — | General | SOC 10 or SOC +1, whichever is higher |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishaps |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured in action (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | Your unit is slaughtered in a disastrous battle, for which you blame your commander. Gain them as an Enemy as they have you removed from the service. |
                    | 3 | You are sent to a very unpleasant region (jungle, swamp, desert, icecap, urban) to battle against guerrilla fighters and rebels. You are discharged because of stress, injury or because the government wishes to bury the whole incident. Increase Recon or Survival by one level but also gain the rebels as an Enemy. |
                    | 4 | You discover that your commanding officer is engaged in some illegal activity, such as weapon smuggling. You can join their ring and gain them as an Ally before the inevitable investigation gets you discharged or you can co-operate with the military police – the official whitewash gets you discharged anyway but you may keep your Benefit roll from this term of service. |
                    | 5 | You are tormented by or quarrel with an officer or fellow soldier. Gain that officer as a Rival as they drive you out of the service. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You are assigned to a planet with a hostile or wild environment. Gain one of Vacc Suit 1, Engineer 1, Animals (riding or training) 1 or Recon 1. |
                    | 4 | You are assigned to an urbanised planet torn by war. Gain one of Stealth 1, Streetwise 1, Persuade 1 or Recon 1. |
                    | 5 | You are given a special assignment or duty in your unit. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 6 | You are thrown into a brutal ground war. Roll EDU 8+ to avoid injury; if you succeed, you gain one level in Gun Combat or Leadership. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 8+ to increase any one skill you already have by one level. |
                    | 9 | Surrounded and outnumbered by the enemy, you hold out until relief arrives. Gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 10 | You are assigned to a peacekeeping role. Gain one of Admin 1, Investigate 1, Deception 1 or Recon 1. |
                    | 11 | Your commanding officer takes an interest in your career. Either gain Tactics (military) 1 or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | You display heroism in battle. You may gain a promotion or a commission automatically. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Citizen">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Citizen
                    ---
                    Individuals serving in a corporation, bureaucracy or industry, or who are making a new life on an untamed planet.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** EDU 5+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Corporate:** You are an executive or manager in a large corporation.
                    **Worker:** You are a blue collar worker on an industrial world.
                    **Colonist:** You are building a new life on a recently settled world that still needs taming.
                    ---
                    **Note:** Use you assignment skill table for basic training, not service skills.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    |  | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Corporate | SOC 6+ | INT 6+ |
                    | Worker | END 4+ | EDU 8+ |
                    | Colonist | INT 7+ | END 5+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr2,000 | Ship Share |
                    | 2 | Cr5,000 | Ally |
                    | 3 | Cr10,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 4 | Cr10,000 | Gun |
                    | 5 | Cr10,000 | EDU +1 |
                    | 6 | Cr50,000 | Two Ship Shares |
                    | 7 | Cr100,000 | TAS Membership |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 10) | Corporate | Worker | Colonist |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | EDU +1 | Drive | Art | Advocate | Drive | Animals |
                    | 2 | INT +1 | Flyer | Advocate | Admin | Mechanic | Athletics |
                    | 3 | Carouse | Streetwise | Diplomat | Broker | Electronics | Jack-of-all-Trades |
                    | 4 | Gambler | Melee | Language | Electronics (computers) | Engineer | Drive |
                    | 5 | Drive | Steward | Electronics (computers) | Diplomat | Profession | Survival |
                    | 6 | Jack-of-all-Trades | Profession | Medic | Leadership | Science | Recon |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Corporate | Skill or Bonus | Worker | Skill or Bonus | Colonist | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 1 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 2 | Manager | Admin 1 | Technician | Profession 1 | Settler | Survival 1 |
                    | 3 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 4 | Senior Manager | Advocate 1 | Craftsman | Mechanic 1 | Explorer | Navigation 1 |
                    | 5 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 6 | Director | SOC +1 | Master Technician | Engineer 1 | — | Gun Combat 1 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | You are harassed and your life ruined by a criminal gang. Gain the gang as an Enemy. |
                    | 3 | Hard times caused by a lack of interstellar trade costs you your job. Lose one SOC. |
                    | 4 | Your business is investigated by the planetary authorities (or your colony suffers interference from interests offworld). Co-operate and the business or colony is shut down but you gain DM+2 to the qualification roll for your next career as a reward for your aid. Refuse and gain an Ally. |
                    | 5 | A revolution, attack or other unusual event throws your life into chaos, forcing you to leave the planet. Roll Streetwise 8+. If you succeed, increase any skill you have by one level. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | Political upheaval strikes your homeworld and you are caught up in the revolution. Gain either Advocate 1, Persuade 1, Explosives 1 or Streetwise 1. Roll whichever skill you chose 8+. If you succeed you come out on the winning side and gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll. Fail and you suffer DM-2 to your next Survival roll. |
                    | 4 | You spend time maintaining and using heavy vehicles, either as part of your job or as a hobby. Increase Mechanic, Drive, Electronics, Flyer or Engineer by one level. |
                    | 5 | Your business expands, your corporation grows or the colony thrives. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 6 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 10+ to gain any one skill of your choice at level 1. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You learn something you should not have – a corporate secret, a political scandal – which you can profit from illegally. If you choose to do so, then you gain DM+1 to a Benefit roll from this career and gain Streetwise 1, Deception 1 or a criminal Contact. If you refuse, you gain nothing. |
                    | 9 | You are rewarded for your diligence or cunning. Gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 10 | You gain experience in a technical field as a computer operator or surveyor. Increase Electronics or Engineer by one level. |
                    | 11 | You befriend a superior in the corporation or the colony. Gain an Ally. Either gain Diplomat 1 or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | You rise to a position of power in your colony or corporation. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Drifter">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Difter
                    ---
                    Wanderers, hitchhikers and travellers, drifters are those who roam the stars without obvious purpose or direction.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** Automatic
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Barbarian:** You live on a primitive world without the benefits of technology.
                    **Wanderer:** You are a space bum, living hand-to-mouth in slums and spaceports across the galaxy.
                    **Scavenger:** You work as a belter (asteroid miner) or on a salvage crew.
                    ---
                    **Note:** Use you assignment skill table for basic training, not service skills.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Barbarian | END 7+ | STR 7+ |
                    | Wanderer | END 7+ | INT 7+ |
                    | Scavenger | DEX 7+ | END 7+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | None | Contact |
                    | 2 | None | Weapon |
                    | 3 | Cr1,000 | Ally |
                    | 4 | Cr2,000 | Weapon |
                    | 5 | Cr3,000 | EDU +1 |
                    | 6 | Cr4,000 | Ship Share |
                    | 7 | Cr8,000 | Two Ship Shares |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Barbarian | Wanderer | Scavenger |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Athletics | Animals | Drive | Pilot (small craft) |
                    | 2 | END +1 | Melee (unarmed) | Carouse | Deception | Mechanic |
                    | 3 | DEX +1 | Recon | Melee (blade) | Recon | Astrogation |
                    | 4 | Language | Streetwise | Stealth | Stealth | Vacc Suit |
                    | 5 | Profession | Stealth | Seafarer (personal or sail) | Streetwise | Profession |
                    | 6 | Jack-of-all-Trades | Survival | Survival | Survival | Gun Combat |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Barbarian | Skill or Bonus | Wanderer | Skill or Bonus | Scavenger | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 1 | — | Survival 1 | — | Streetwise 1 | — | Vacc Suit 1 |
                    | 2 | Warrior | Melee (blade) 1 | — | — | — | — |
                    | 3 | — | — | — | Deception 1 | — | Profession (belter) 1 or Mechanic 1 |
                    | 4 | Chieftain | Leadership 1 | — | — | — | — |
                    | 5 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 6 | Warlord | — | — | — | — | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                    | 3 | You run afoul of a criminal gang, corrupt bureaucrat or other foe. Gain an Enemy. |
                    | 4 | You suffer from a life-threatening illness. Reduce your END by 1. |
                    | 5 | Betrayed by a friend. One of your Contacts or Allies betrays you, ending your career. That Contact or Ally becomes a Rival or Enemy. If you have no Contacts or Allies, then you are betrayed by someone you never saw coming and still gain a Rival or Enemy. In addition, roll 2D. If you roll 2, you must take the Prisoner career in your next term. |
                    | 6 | You do not know what happened to you. There is a gap in your memory. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | A patron offers you a chance at a job. If you accept, you gain DM+4 to your next qualification roll but you owe that patron a favour. |
                    | 4 | You pick up a few useful skills here and there. Gain one level of Jack-of-all-Trades, Survival, Streetwise or Melee (any). |
                    | 5 | You manage to scavenge something of use. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 6 | You encounter something unusual. Go to the Life Events table and have an Unusual Event. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You are attacked by enemies. Gain an Enemy if you do not have one already and roll either Melee 8+, Gun Combat 8+ or Stealth 8+ to avoid a roll on the Injury table. |
                    | 9 | You are offered a chance to take part in a risky but rewarding adventure. If you accept, roll 1D: On a 1–2, you are injured or arrested; either roll on the Injury table or take the Prisoner career in your next term. On 3–4, you survive, but gain nothing. On a 5–6, you succeed. Gain DM+4 to one Benefit roll. |
                    | 10 | Life on the edge hones your abilities. Increase any skill you already have by one level. |
                    | 11 | You are forcibly drafted. Roll for the Draft next term. |
                    | 12 | You thrive on adversity. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Entertainer">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Entertainer
                    ---
                    Individuals who are involved with the media, whether as reporters, artists or celebrities.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** DEX or INT 5+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Artist:** You are a writer, holographer or other creative.
                    **Journalist:** You report on local or galactic events for a news feed, the TAS or other organisation.
                    **Performer:** You are an actor, dancer, acrobat, professional athlete or other public performer.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Artist | SOC 6+ | INT 6+ |
                    | Journalist | EDU 7+ | INT 5+ |
                    | Performer | INT 5+ | DEX 7+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | None | Contact |
                    | 2 | None | SOC +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr10,000 | Contact |
                    | 4 | Cr10,000 | SOC +1 |
                    | 5 | Cr40,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 6 | Cr40,000 | Two Ship Shares |
                    | 7 | Cr80,000 | SOC +1 and EDU +1 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 10) | Artist | Journalist | Performer |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | DEX +1 | Art | Advocate | Art | Art (holography or write) | Art (performer or instrument) |
                    | 2 | INT +1 | Carouse | Broker | Carouse | Electronics | Athletics |
                    | 3 | SOC +1 | Deception | Deception | Electronics (computers) | Drive | Carouse |
                    | 4 | Language | Drive | Science | Gambler | Investigate | Deception |
                    | 5 | Carouse | Persuade | Streetwise | Persuade | Recon | Stealth |
                    | 6 | Jack-of-all-Trades | Steward | Diplomat | Profession | Streetwise | Streetwise |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Ranks | Artist | Skill or Bonus | Journalist | Skill or Bonus | Performer | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 1 | — | Art 1 | Freelancer | Electronics (comms) 1 | — | DEX +1 |
                    | 2 | — | — | Staff Writer | Investigate 1 | — | — |
                    | 3 | — | Investigate 1 | — | — | — | STR +1 |
                    | 4 | — | — | Correspondent | Persuade 1 | — | — |
                    | 5 | Famouse Artist | SOC +1 | — | — | Famouse Performer | SOC +1 |
                    | 6 | — | — | Senior Correspondent | SOC +1 | — | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | You expose or are involved in a scandal of some sort. |
                    | 3 | Public opinion turns on you. Reduce your SOC by 1. |
                    | 4 | You are betrayed by a peer. One of your Contacts or Allies betrays you, ending your career. That Contact or Ally becomes a Rival or Enemy. If you have no Contacts or Allies, then you are betrayed by someone you never saw coming and still gain a Rival or Enemy. |
                    | 5 | An investigation, tour, project or expedition goes wrong, stranding you far from home. Gain one of Survival 1, Pilot 1, Persuade 1 or Streetwise 1. |
                    | 6 | You are forced out because of censorship or controversy. What truth did you get too close to? You gain DM+2 to the qualification roll for your next career. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You are invited to take part in a controversial event or exhibition. Roll Art or Investigate 8+. If you succeed, gain one SOC. If you fail, lose one SOC. |
                    | 4 | You are a part of your homeworld’s celebrity circles. Gain one of Carouse 1, Persuade 1, Steward 1 or a Contact. |
                    | 5 | One of your works is especially well received and popular, making you a minor celebrity. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 6 | You gain a patron in the arts. Gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll and an Ally. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You have the opportunity to criticise or even bring down a questionable political leader on your homeworld. If you refuse and support the leader, you gain nothing. If you accept, gain an Enemy and roll Art or Persuade 8+. If you succeed, gain one level in any skill you already have. If you fail, increase a skill anyway and roll on the Mishap table. |
                    | 9 | You go on a tour of the sector, visiting several worlds. Gain D3 Contacts. |
                    | 10 | One of your pieces of art is stolen and the investigation brings you into the criminal underworld. Gain one of Streetwise 1, Investigate 1, Recon 1 or Stealth 1. |
                    | 11 | As an artist, you lead a strange and charmed life. Go to the Life Events Table and have an Unusual Event. |
                    | 12 | You win a prestigious prize. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Marine">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Marine
                    ---
                    Members of the armed fighting forces carried aboard starships, marines deal with piracy and boarding actions in space, defend the starports and bases belonging to the navy and supplement ground forces such as the army.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** END 6+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                    DM-2 if you are aged 30 or more
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Support:** You are a quartermaster, engineer or battlefield medic in the marines.
                    **Star Marine:** You are trained to fight boarding actions and capture enemy vessels.
                    **Ground Assault:** You are kicked out of a spacecraft in high orbit and told to ‘capture that planet’.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Support | END 5+ | EDU 7+ |
                    | Star Marine | END 6+ | EDU 6+ |
                    | Ground Assault | END 7+ | EDU 5+ |
                    **Commission:** SOC 8+
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr2,000 | Armour |
                    | 2 | Cr5,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr5,000 | EDU +1 |
                    | 4 | Cr10,000 | Weapon |
                    | 5 | Cr20,000 | TAS Membership |
                    | 6 | Cr30,000 | Armour or END +1 |
                    | 7 | Cr40,000 | SOC +2 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 10) | Officer (Commissioned Only) | Artist | Journalist | Performer |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Athletics | Medic | Electronics | Electronics | Vacc Suit | Vacc Suit |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Vacc Suit | Survival | Tactics | Mechanic | Athletics | Heavy Weapons |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Tactics | Explosives | Admin | Drive or Flyer | Gunner | Recon |
                    | 4 | Gambler | Heavy Weapons | Engineer | Advocate | Medic | Melee (blade) | Melee (blade) |
                    | 5 | Melee (unarmed) | Gun Combat | Pilot | Diplomat | Heavy Weapons | Electronics | Tactics (military) |
                    | 6 | Melee (blade) | Stealth | Navigation | Leadership | Gun Combat | Gun Combat | Gun Combat |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Ranks | Enlisted | Skill or Bonus | Officer | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | Marine | Gun Combat (any) or Melee (blade) 1 | | |
                    | 1 | Lance Corporal | Gun Combat (any) 1 | Lieutenant | Leadership 1 |
                    | 2 | Corporal | — | Captain | — |
                    | 3 | Lance Sergeant | Leadership 1 | Force Commander | Tactics 1 |
                    | 4 | Sergeant | — | Lieutentnt Colonel | — |
                    | 5 | Gunnery Sergeant | END +1 | Colonel | SOC 10 or SOC +1, whichever is higher |
                    | 6 | Sergeant Major | — | Brigadier | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured in action (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | A mission goes wrong; you and several others are captured and mistreated by the enemy. Due to your injuries, you are discharged early. Gain your jailer as an Enemy and reduce your STR and DEX by one because of your injuries. |
                    | 3 | A mission goes wrong and you are stranded behind enemy lines. Increase Stealth or Survival by one level but, due to the mission’s failure, you are ejected from the service. |
                    | 4 | You are ordered to take part in a black ops mission that goes against your conscience. If you refuse you are ejected from the service. If you accept you may stay with the marines but gain the lone survivor as an Enemy. |
                    | 5 | You are tormented by or quarrel with an officer or fellow marine. Gain that character as a Rival as they drive you out of the service. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | Trapped behind enemy lines, you have to survive on your own. Gain one of Survival 1, Stealth 1, Deception 1 or Streetwise 1. |
                    | 4 | You are assigned to the security staff of a space station. Increase Vacc Suit or Athletics (dexterity) by one level. |
                    | 5 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 8+ to gain any one skill of your choice at level 1. |
                    | 6 | You are assigned to an assault on an enemy fortress. Roll Melee or Gun Combat 8+ and gain Tactics (military) or Leadership if you succeed. If you fail, you are injured and lose 1 point from any physical characteristic. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You are on the front lines of a planetary assault and occupation. Gain one of Recon 1, Gun Combat 1, Leadership 1 or Electronics (comms) 1. |
                    | 9 | A mission goes disastrously wrong due to your commander’s error or incompetence but you survive. If you report your commanding officer for their failure then you gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll and gain the officer as an Enemy. If you say nothing and protect them, gain them as an Ally. |
                    | 10 | You are assigned to a black ops mission. Gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 11 | Your commanding officer takes an interest in your career. Either gain Tactics 1 or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | You display heroism in battle. You may gain a promotion or a commission automatically. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Merchant">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Merchant
                    ---
                    Members of a commercial enterprise. Merchants may crew the ships of the huge trading corporations or they may work for independent free traders who carry chance cargoes and passengers between worlds.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** INT 4+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Merchant Marine:** You work on one of the massive cargo haulers run by the Imperium or a megacorporation.
                    **Free Trader:** You are part of the crew of a tramp trader.
                    **Broker:** You work in a planetside brokerage or starport.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Merchant Marine | EDU 5+ | INT 7+ |
                    | Free Trader | DEX 6+ | INT 6+ |
                    | Broker | EDU 5+ | INT 7+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr1,000 | Blade |
                    | 2 | Cr5,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr10,000 | EDU +1 |
                    | 4 | Cr20,000 | Gun |
                    | 5 | Cr20,000 | Ship Share |
                    | 6 | Cr40,000 | Free Trader |
                    | 7 | Cr40,000 | Free Trader |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 8) | Merchant Marine | Free Trader | Broker |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Drive | Engineer | Pilot | Pilot (spacecraft) | Admin |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Vacc Suit | Astrogation | Vacc Suit | Vacc Suit | Advocate |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Broker | Electronics | Athletics | Deception | Broker |
                    | 4 | INT +1 | Steward | Pilot | Mechanic | Mechanic | Streetwise |
                    | 5 | Language | Electronics | Admin | Engineer | Streetwise | Deception |
                    | 6 | Streetwise | Persuade | Advocate | Electronics | Gunner | Persuade |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Merchant Marine | Skill or Bonus | Free Trader | Skill or Bonus | Broker | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | Crewman | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 1 | Senior Crewman | Mechanic 1 | — | Persuade 1 | — | Broker 1 |
                    | 2 | 4th Officer | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 3 | 3rd Officer | — | Experienced Trader | Jack-of-all-Trades 1 | Experienced Broker | Streetwise 1 |
                    | 4 | 2nd Officer | Pilot 1 | — | — | — | — |
                    | 5 | 1st Officer | SOC +1 | — | — | — | — |
                    | 6 | Captain | — | — | — | — | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | You are bankrupted by a rival. You lose all Benefits from this career and gain the other trader as a Rival. |
                    | 3 | A sudden war destroys your trade routes and contacts, forcing you to flee that region of space. Gain Gun Combat 1 or Pilot 1. |
                    | 4 | Your ship or starport is destroyed by criminals. Gain them as an Enemy. |
                    | 5 | Imperial trade restrictions force you out of business. You may take the Rogue career for your next term without needing to roll for qualification. |
                    | 6 | A series of bad deals and decisions force you into bankruptcy. You salvage what you can. You may take a Benefit roll for this term as well as any others you are entitled to. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You are offered the opportunity to smuggle illegal items onto a planet. If you accept, roll Deception 8+ or Persuade 8+ to gain Streetwise 1 and an extra Benefit roll. If you refuse, you gain an Enemy in the criminal sphere. |
                    | 4 | Gain any one of these skills, reflecting your time spent dealing with suppliers and spacers: Profession 1, Electronics 1, Engineer 1, Animals 1 or Science 1. |
                    | 5 | You have a chance to risk your fortune on a possibility lucrative deal. You may gamble a number of Benefit rolls and roll Gambler 8+ or Broker 8+. If you succeed, you gain half as many Benefit rolls as you risked, rounding up. If you fail, you lose all the rolls risked. Either way, gain one level in whichever skill you used. |
                    | 6 | You make an unexpected connection outside your normal circles. Gain a Contact. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You are embroiled in legal trouble. Gain one of Advocate 1, Admin 1, Diplomat 1 or Investigate 1, then roll 2D. If you roll 2, you must take the Prisoner career in your next term. |
                    | 9 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 8+ to increase any one skill you already have by one level. |
                    | 10 | A good deal ensures you are living the high life for a few years. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 11 | You befriend a useful ally in one sphere. Gain an Ally and either gain a level in Carouse or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | Your business or ship thrives. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Navy">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Navy
                    ---
                    Members of the interstellar navy that patrols space between the stars. The navy has the responsibility for the protection of society from foreign powers and lawless elements in the interstellar trade channels.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** INT 6+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                    DM-2 if you are aged 34 or more
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Line/Crew:** You serve as a general crewman or officer on a ship of the line.
                    **Engineer/Gunner:** You serve as a specialist technician on a starship.
                    **Flight:** You are a pilot of a shuttle, fighter or other light craft.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Line/Crew | INT 5+ | EDU 7+ |
                    | Engineer/Gunner | INT 6+ | EDU 6+ |
                    | Flight | DEX 7+ | EDU 5+ |
                    **Commission:** SOC 8+
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr1,000 | Personal Vehicle or Ship Share |
                    | 2 | Cr5,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr5,000 | EDU +1 or two Ship Shares |
                    | 4 | Cr10,000 | Weapon |
                    | 5 | Cr20,000 | TAS Membership |
                    | 6 | Cr50,000 | Ship's Boat or two Ship Shares |
                    | 7 | Cr50,000 | SOC +2 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 8) | Officer (Commissioned Only) | Line/Crew | Engineer/Gunner | Flight |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Pilot | Electronics | Leadership | Electronics | Engineer | Pilot |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Vacc Suit | Astrogation | Electronics | Mechanic | Mechanic | Flyer |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Athletics | Engineer | Pilot | Gun Combat | Electronics | Gunner |
                    | 4 | INT +1 | Gunner | Flyer | Melee (blade) | Flyer | Engineer | Pilot (small craft) |
                    | 5 | EDU +1 | Mechanic | Medic | Admin | Melee | Gunner | Astrogation |
                    | 6 | SOC +1 | Gun Combat | Admin | Tactics (naval) | Vacc Suit | Flyer | Electronics |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Enlisted | Skill or Bonus | Officer | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | Crewman | — | | |
                    | 1 | Able Spacehand | Mechanic 1 | Ensign | Melee (blade) 1 |
                    | 2 | Petty Officer, 3rd class | Vacc Suit 1 | Sublieutenant | Leadership 1 |
                    | 3 | Petty Officer, 2nd class | — | Lieutenant | — |
                    | 4 | Petty Officer, 1st class | END +1 | Commander | Tactics (naval) 1 |
                    | 5 | Chief Petty Officer | — | Captain | SOC 10 or SOC +1, whichever is higher |
                    | 6 | Master Chief | — | Admiral | SOC 12 or SOC +1, whichever is higher |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured in action (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | Placed in the frozen watch (cryogenically stored on board ship) and revived improperly. Reduce STR, DEX or END by 1 due to muscle wastage. You are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | During a battle, defeat or victory depends on your actions. You must make an 8+ roll using a skill that depends on your branch: Electronics (sensors) or Gunner if you are crew, Mechanic or Vacc Suit if you are engineer/gunner and Pilot (small craft or spacecraft) or Tactics (naval) if you are flight. If you fail, the ship suffers severe damage and you are blamed for the disaster. You are court-martialled and discharged. If you succeed, your efforts ensure that you are honourably discharged. You still leave the career but may keep your Benefit roll from this term. |
                    | 4 | You are blamed for an accident that causes the death of several crew members. If you were responsible, then you gain one free roll on the Skills and Training tables before you are ejected from this career as your guilt drives you to excel. If you were not, then gain the officer who blamed you as an Enemy but you keep your Benefit roll from this term. |
                    | 5 | You are tormented by or quarrel with an officer or fellow crewman. Gain that character as a Rival, as they force you out of the Navy. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You join a gambling circle on board. Gain Gambler 1 or Deception 1. If you wish, throw Gambler 8+. If you succeed, gain an extra Benefit roll from this career; if you fail, you lose one Benefit roll from this career. |
                    | 4 | You are given a special assignment or duty on board ship. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 5 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 8+ to gain one level in any skill you already have. |
                    | 6 | Your vessel participates in a notable military engagement. Gain one of Electronics 1, Engineer 1, Gunner 1 or Pilot 1. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | Your vessel participates in a diplomatic mission. Gain one of Recon 1, Diplomat 1, Steward 1 or a Contact. |
                    | 9 | You foil an attempted crime on board, such as mutiny, sabotage, smuggling or conspiracy. Gain an Enemy but also gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll in the Navy. |
                    | 10 | You have the opportunity to abuse your position for profit. If you do so, gain an extra Benefit roll from this term. Refuse and you get DM+2 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 11 | Your commanding officer takes an interest in your career. Either gain Tactics (naval) 1 or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | You display heroism in battle, saving the whole ship. You automatically pass your next promotion or commission roll. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Noble">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Noble
                    ---
                    Individuals of the upper class who perform little consistent function but often have large amounts of ready money.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** SOC 10+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                    Automatic qualification if your SOC is 10 or higher
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Administrator:** You serve in the planetary government or even ruled over a fiefdom or other domain.
                    **Diplomat:** You are a diplomat or other state official.
                    **Dilettante:** You are known for being known and have absolutely no useful function in society.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Administrator | INT 4+ | EDU 6+ |
                    | Diplomat | INT 5+ | SOC 7+ |
                    | Dilettante | SOC 5+ | INT 7+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr10,000 | Ship Share |
                    | 2 | Cr10,000 | Two Ship Shares |
                    | 3 | Cr50,000 | Blade |
                    | 4 | Cr50,000 | SOC +1 |
                    | 5 | Cr100,000 | TAS Membership |
                    | 6 | Cr100,000 | Yacht |
                    | 7 | Cr200,000 | SOC +1 and Yacht |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 8) | Administrator | Diplomat | Dilettante |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Admin | Science | Admin | Advocate | Carouse |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Advocate | Advocate | Advocate | Carouse | Deception |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Electronics | Language | Broker | Electronics | Flyer |
                    | 4 | Gambler | Diplomat | Leadership | Diplomat | Steward | Streetwise |
                    | 5 | Gun Combat | Investigate | Diplomat | Leadership | Diplomat | Gambler |
                    | 6 | Melee | Persuade | Art | Persuade | Deception | Jack-of-all-Trades |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Administrator | Skill or Bonus | Diplomat | Skill or Bonus | Dilettante | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | Assistant | — | Intern | — | Wastrel | — |
                    | 1 | Clerk | Admin 1 | 3rd Secretary | Admin 1 | — | — |
                    | 2 | Supervisor | — | 2nd Secretary | — | Ingrate | Carouse 1 |
                    | 3 | Manager | Advocate 1 | 1st Secretary | Advocate 1 | — | — |
                    | 4 | Chief | — | Counsellor | — | Black Sheep | Persuade 1 |
                    | 5 | Director | Leadership 1 | Minister | Diplomat 1 | — | — |
                    | 6 | Minister | — | Ambassador | — | Scoundrel | Jack-of-all-Trades 1 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap|
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | A family scandal forces you out of your position. Lose one SOC. |
                    | 3 | A disaster or war strikes. Roll Stealth 8+ or Deception 8+ to escape unhurt. If you fail, roll on the Injury table. |
                    | 4 | Political manoeuvrings usurp your position. Increase Diplomat or Advocate by one level and gain a Rival. |
                    | 5 | An assassin attempts to end your life. Roll END 8+. If you fail, roll on the Injury table. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table , but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You are challenged to a duel for your honour and standing. If you refuse, reduce your SOC by 1. If you accept, roll Melee (blade) 8+. If you succeed, gain one SOC. If you fail, roll on the Injury table and reduce your SOC by one. Either way, gain one level in Melee (blade), Leadership, Tactics (any) or Deception. |
                    | 4 | Your time as a ruler or playboy gives you a wide range of experiences. Gain one of Animals (handling) 1, Art 1, Carouse 1 or Streetwise 1. |
                    | 5 | You inherit a gift from a rich relative. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 6 | You become deeply involved in politics on your world of residence, becoming a player in the political intrigues of government. Gain one level in Advocate, Admin, Diplomacy or Persuade but also gain a Rival. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | A conspiracy of nobles attempts to recruit you. If you refuse, gain the conspiracy as an Enemy. If you accept, roll Deception 8+ or Persuade 8+. If you fail, roll on the Mishap table as the conspiracy collapses. If you succeed, Gain one level of Deception, Persuade, Tactics or Carouse. |
                    | 9 | Your reign is acclaimed by all as being fair and wise – or in the case of a dilettante, you sponge off your family’s wealth a while longer. Gain either a jealous relative or an unhappy subject as an Enemy. Gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 10 | You manipulate and charm your way through high society. Gain one level of Carouse, Diplomat, Persuade or Steward, as well as a Rival and an Ally. |
                    | 11 | You make an alliance with a powerful and charismatic noble, who becomes an Ally. Either gain one level of Leadership or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | Your efforts do not go unnoticed by the Imperium. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Prisoner">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Prisoner
                    ---
                    Every society has its bad apples and even in the far future punishments usually take place within faceless institutions where criminals can be conveniently forgotten.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** Special. One does not ‘qualify’ for prison; you got sentenced there for a crime you may or may not have committed.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Inmate:** You just try to get through your time in prison without getting into trouble.
                    **Thug:** You are part of a gang in prison, terrorising the other inmates.
                    **Fixer:** You can arrange anything – for the right price.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Inmate | END 7+ | STR 7+ |
                    | Thug | STR 8+ | END 6+ |
                    | Fixer | INT 9+ | END 5+ |
                    ---
                    A Traveller may not normally leave or be ejected from this career – not even Mishaps will force them to leave. Instead, they have a value called a Parole Threshold. At the end of each term in the prisoner career, if the Traveller’s advancement roll is greater than their Parole Threshold, it means their prison sentence has come to an end and they leave this career. Otherwise, they may not leave this career and must continue in it for another term.
                    A Traveller’s Parole Threshold starts at 1D+2. A Traveller’s Parole Threshold can never go above 12.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | None | Contact |
                    | 2 | None | Blade |
                    | 3 | Cr100 | Deception, Persuade or Stealth |
                    | 4 | Cr200 | Ally |
                    | 5 | Cr500 | Melee, Recon or Streetwise |
                    | 6 | Cr1,000 | STR +1 or END +1 |
                    | 7 | Cr2,500 | Deception, Persuade or Stealth |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Inmate | Thug | Fixer |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Athletics | Stealth | Persuade | Investigate |
                    | 2 | Melee (unarmed) | Deception | Melee (unarmed) | Melee (unarmed) | Broker |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Profession | Streetwise | Melee (unarmed) | Deception |
                    | 4 | Jack-of-all-Trades | Streetwise | Survival | Melee (blade) | Streetwise |
                    | 5 | EDU +1 | Melee (unarmed) | Athletics (strength) | Athletics (strength) | Stealth |
                    | 6 | Gambler | Persuade | Mechanic | Athletics (strength) | Admin |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | Melee (unarmed) 1 |
                    | 1 | — |
                    | 2 | Athletics 1 |
                    | 3 | — |
                    | 4 | Advocate 1 |
                    | 5 | — |
                    | 6 | END +1 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | You are accused of assaulting a prison guard. Parole Threshold +2. |
                    | 3 | A prison gang persecutes you. You may choose to fight back if you wish but, if you do not, you lose all Benefit rolls from your Prisoner career. If you fight back, roll Melee (unarmed) 8+. Fail and you must roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. Succeed and you gain an Enemy and raise Parole Threshold by +1. |
                    | 4 | A guard takes a dislike to you. Gain an Enemy and raise your Parole Threshold by +1. |
                    | 5 | Disgraced. Word of your criminal past reaches your homeworld. Lose 1 SOC. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table. However, you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You have the opportunity to escape the prison. If you take this opportunity, roll either Stealth 10+ or Deception 10+. Succeed and you leave this career. Fail and raise your Parole Threshold by +2. |
                    | 4 | You are assigned to difficult or backbreaking labour. Roll END 8+. If you fail, increase your Parole Threshold by +1. Succeed and you may reduce your Parole Threshold by 1 and gain any one of the following skills: Athletics (any) 1, Mechanic 1, or Melee (unarmed) 1. |
                    | 5 | You have the opportunity to join a gang. Roll Persuade or Melee 8+ to do so. If you fail, you gain an Enemy. Succeed and you must raise your Parole Threshold by +1 but gain DM+1 to all survival rolls in this career and any one of the following skills: Deception 1, Persuade 1, Melee (unarmed) 1 or Stealth 1. |
                    | 6 | Vocational Training. Roll EDU 8+ to gain any one skill except Jack-of-all-Trades. |
                    | 7 | Roll a Prison Event below |
                    | 8 | Parole hearing. Reduce your Parole Threshold by -1. |
                    | 9 | You have the opportunity to hire a new lawyer, with your choice of Advocate skill. They cost Cr1000 x their Advocate level squared. Roll 2D + your lawyer’s Advocate skill; on an 8+, reduce your Parole Threshold by 1D. |
                    | 10 | Special Duty. You are given a special responsibility in the prison. Gain one of Admin, Advocate, Electronics (computers) or Steward. |
                    | 11 | The warden takes an interest in your case. Reduce your Parole Threshold by -2. |
                    | 12 | Heroism. You have the opportunity to save a guard or prison officer. If you take the risk, roll 2D. On a 7 or less, roll on the Injury table. On 8+, gain an Ally and reduce your Parole Threshold by -2. |
                    ---
                    | 1D | Prison Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Riot. A riot engulfs the prison. Roll 1D. On a 1–2, you are injured – roll on the Injury table. On a 5–6, you are able to loot something useful; gain an extra Benefit roll this term. |
                    | 2 | New Contact. You make friends with another inmate; gain them as a Contact. |
                    | 3 | New Rival. You gain a new Rival among the inmates or guards. |
                    | 4 | Transferred. You are moved to a different prison. Re-roll your Parole Threshold. |
                    | 5 | Good Behaviour. Reduce your Parole Threshold by -2. |
                    | 6 | You are attacked by another prisoner. Roll Melee (unarmed) 8+. If you fail, roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Psion">
            <button title="Psionics">
                <markdown>
                    # Psionics
                    ---
                    In Traveller, a few humans (and aliens) have developed potent psionic abilities such as telepathy, telekinesis and even teleportation. Learning to properly control psionics is never easy and their use cannot always be relied upon but they are guaranteed to provide their practitioners with a dangerous edge simply not possible for normal humans.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="The Law">
                <markdown>
                    # The Imperium: Psionics and the Law
                    ---
                    In the Charted Space universe, learning to harness psionics is a difficult process, made harder by the Third Imperium’s ban on psionics. The Psionics Institutes that study mental powers have gone underground, following a disastrous attempt to guide human development centuries ago. In other civilisations, such as the Zhodani Consulate, psionics are a fully accepted part of the human condition.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Psionic Strength">
                <markdown>
                    # Pisonic Strength
                    ---
                    Psionics are powered by the Psionic Strength (PSI) characteristic. This characteristic cannot be rolled during Traveller creation without the referee’s permission and even then it is quite rare. To determine a Traveller’s PSI, roll 2D and subtract the number of terms served by the Traveller in all careers thus far (PSI diminishes over time unless actively used). For example, a 38 year old Traveller (five terms served) would roll 2D–5 to determine their PSI. A Traveller with PSI 0 has no potential for psionic talents.
                    Using a psionic power costs a number of PSI points, temporarily reducing the Traveller’s total. As the characteristic DM for all psionic skill checks is determined by the Travellers’ current PSI total, it gets harder and harder to use powers as the Traveller’s PSI declines.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Institute Testing">
                <markdown>
                    # Institute Testing
                    ---
                    A Traveller who wishes to develop psionic abilities requires training. In settings where psionics are uncommon or illegal, the Traveller must find a teacher, normally an underground Psionics Institute. Finding such an instructor can be an adventure in itself. Most teachers will charge at least Cr5000 to test the Traveller’s abilities. Testing takes two weeks.
                    The first step is testing a Traveller’s PSI, which is determined as described before (2D minus the number of terms served). If the Traveller has any PSI remaining, they can be trained.
                    Training requires four months of work and costs Cr100000. As part of training, the Traveller may attempt to learn any of the common psionic talents on the Psionic Training table by making a PSI check. They may attempt the talents in any order but suffer DM–1 per check attempted. If a Traveller learns a talent, they gain it at skill level 0.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Telepathic Potential">
                <markdown>
                    # Telepathic Potential
                    ---
                    Telepaths are by far the most common among those with psionic potential. If a Traveller chooses Telepathy as their first talent, it will be gained automatically with no need to roll on the Psionic Training table.
                    ---
                    ### Psionic Training
                    | Talent | Learning DM |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | Telepathy | +4 |
                    | Clairvoyance | +3 |
                    | Telekinesis | +2 |
                    | Awareness | +1 |
                    | Teleporation | + 0 |
                    | Per previous talent acquisition check | -1 |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Pison Career">
                <markdown>
                    # Using the Psion Career
                    ---
                    A Traveller may only attempt to enter the Psion career with the permission of the referee normally because of the single Life Event that allows it.
                    Unlike other careers, a Psion takes skills from the appropriate Specialist table instead of the Service Skills table during basic training.
                    The Psion must still roll to acquire talents when they determine their PSI. When rolling on the Service Skills table, if the Psion gains the skill for a talent they do not yet possess, they may attempt another roll to learn that talent.
                    The assignments for Psions are considered to be separate careers and a Traveller must roll for qualification as normal if they choose to change assignment during their career.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Pison
                    ---
                    A career for Travellers who choose to focus on their psionic potential instead of more conventional lifestyles.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** PSI 6+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Wild Talent:** You developed your powers without formal training.
                    **Adept:** You are a scholar of the psionic disciplines.
                    **Psi-Warrior:** You combine combat training with psionic warfare.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Wild Talent | SOC 6+ | INT 8+ |
                    | Adept | EDU 4+ | EDU 8+ |
                    | Psi-Warrior | END 6+ | END 6+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr1,000 | Gun |
                    | 2 | Cr2,000 | Two Ship Shares |
                    | 3 | Cr4,000 | Contact |
                    | 4 | Cr4,000 | TAS Membership |
                    | 5 | Cr8,000 | Contact |
                    | 6 | Cr8,000 | Combat Implant |
                    | 7 | Cr16,000 | 10 Ship Shares |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 8) | Wild Talent | Adept | Psi-Warrior |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | EDU +1 | Telepathy | Language | Telepathy | Telepathy | Telepathy |
                    | 2 | INT +1 | Clairvoyance | Art | Telekinesis | Clairvoyance | Awareness |
                    | 3 | STR +1 | Telekinesis | Electronics | Deception | Awareness | Teleportation |
                    | 4 | DEX +1 | Awareness | Medic | Stealth | Medic | Gun Combat |
                    | 5 | END +1 | Teleportation | Science | Streetwise | Persuade | Vacc Suit |
                    | 6 | PSI +1 | Any Talent | Mechanic | Melee or Gun Combat | Science | Recon |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Wild Talent | Skill or Bonus | Adept | Skill or Bonus | Psi-Warrior | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | — | — | — | — | Psi-Solider | —
                    | 1 | Survivor | Survival 1 or Streetwise 1 | Initiate | Science (psioncology) 1 | — | Gun Combat 1 |
                    | 2 | — | — | — | — | Knight | Leadership 1 |
                    | 3 | Witch | Deception 1 | Acolyte | Any Talent skill 1 | — | — |
                    | 4 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 5 | — | — | — | — | Master of Wills | Tactics 1 |
                    | 6 | — | — | Master | Any Talent skill 1 | — | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | You telepathically contact something dangerous. Lose one PSI. You also suffer from persistent and terrifying nightmares. |
                    | 3 | An anti-psi cult or gang attempts to expose or attack you. Roll 1D: on a 1–2, you are injured, roll on the Injury table. On a 3–4, lose one SOC. On a 5–6, nothing else happens but you still must leave this career. |
                    | 4 | You are asked to use your psionic powers in an unethical fashion. Accept and you may continue in this career but gain an Enemy. Refuse and you must leave the career. |
                    | 5 | You are experimented on by a corporation, government or other organisation. You escape but are forced to leave this career. |
                    | 6 | Your gift causes a former friend to turn on you and betray you. One Ally or Contact becomes an Enemy. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button title="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | Your psionic abilities make you uncomfortable to be around. One Contact or Ally becomes a Rival. |
                    | 4 | Choose one of these skills, reflecting your time spent mastering mind and body. Gain one of Athletics 1, Stealth 1, Survival 1 or Art 1. |
                    | 5 | You have a chance to use your powers unethically to better your standing. If you accept, roll PSI 8+. If you succeed, gain an extra Benefit roll or +1 SOC. If you fail, lose one SOC. |
                    | 6 | You make an unexpected connection outside your normal circles. Gain a Contact. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You achieve a new level of psionic strength. Increase your PSI by +1. |
                    | 9 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 8+ to gain any one skill except Jackof-all-Trades. |
                    | 10 | You pick up potentially useful information using your psychic powers. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 11 | You gain a mentor. Gain an Ally and DM+4 to your next advancement roll (in any career) thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | You achieve a new level of discipline in your powers. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Rogue">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Rogue
                    ---
                    Criminal elements familiar with the rougher or more illegal methods of attaining goals.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** DEX 6+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Thief:** You steal from the rich and give to… well, yourself, actually.
                    **Enforcer:** You are a leg breaker, thug or assassin for a criminal group.
                    **Pirate:** You are a space-going corsair.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Thief | INT 6+ | DEX 6+ |
                    | Enforcer | END 6+ | STR 6+ |
                    | Pirate | DEX 6+ | INT 6+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    |--- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | None | Ship Share |
                    | 2 | None | Weapon |
                    | 3 | Cr10,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 4 | Cr10,000 | 1D Ship Shares |
                    | 5 | Cr50,000 | Armour |
                    | 6 | Cr100,000 | DEX +1 |
                    | 7 | Cr100,000 | 2D Ship Shares |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 10) | Thief | Enforcer | Pirate |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Carouse | Deception | Electronics | Stealth | Gun Combat | Pilot |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Recon | Navigation | Electronics | Melee | Astrogation |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Athletics | Medic | Recon | Streetwise | Gunner |
                    | 4 | Gambler | Gun Combat | Investigate | Streetwise | Persuade | Engineer |
                    | 5 | Melee | Stealth | Broker | Deception | Athletics | Vacc Suit |
                    | 6 | Gun Combat | Streetwise | Advocate | Athletics | Drive | Melee |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Thief | Skill or Bonus | Enforcer | Skill or Bonus | Pirate | Skill or Bonus |
                    | 0 | — | — | — | — | Lackey | — |
                    | 1 | — | Stealth 1 | — | Persuade 1 | Henchman | Pilot 1 or Gunner 1 |
                    | 2 | — | — | — | — | Corporal | — |
                    | 3 | — | Streetwise 1 | — | Gun Combat 1 or Melee 1 | Sergeant | Gun Combat 1 or Melee 1 |
                    | 4 | — | — | — | — | Lieutenant | — |
                    | 5 | — | Recon 1 | — | Streetwise 1 | Leader | Leadership 1 |
                    | 6 | — | — | — | — | Captain | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | Arrested. You must take the Prisoner career in your next term. |
                    | 3 | Betrayed by a friend. One of your Contacts or Allies betrays you, ending your career. That Contact or Ally becomes a Rival or Enemy. If you have no Contacts or Allies, then you are betrayed by someone you never saw coming and still gain a Rival or Enemy. In addition, roll 2D. If you roll 2, you must take the Prisoner career in your next term. |
                    | 4 | A job goes wrong, forcing you to flee off-planet. Gain one of Deception 1, Pilot (small craft or spacecraft) 1, Athletics (dexterity) 1 or Gunner 1. |
                    | 5 | A police detective or rival criminal forces you to flee and vows to hunt you down. Gain an Enemy. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You are arrested and charged. You can choose to defend yourself or hire a lawyer. If you defend yourself, roll Advocate 8+. If you succeed, the charges are dropped. If you fail, gain an Enemy and take the Prisoner career in your next term. If you hired a lawyer, gain the lawyer as a Contact and lose a Benefit roll. |
                    | 4 | You are involved in the planning of an impressive heist. Gain Electronics 1 or Mechanic 1. |
                    | 5 | One of your crimes pays off. Gain DM+2 to any one Benefit roll and gain your victim as an Enemy. |
                    | 6 | You have the opportunity to backstab a fellow rogue for personal gain. If you do so, gain DM+4 to your next advancement roll. If you refuse, gain them as an Ally. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You spend months in the dangerous criminal underworld. Gain one of Streetwise 1, Stealth 1, Melee 1 or Gun Combat 1. |
                    | 9 | You become involved in a feud with a rival criminal organisation. Roll Stealth or Gun Combat 8+. If you fail, roll on the Injury Table. If you succeed, gain an extra Benefit roll. |
                    | 10 | You are involved in a gambling ring. Gain Gambler 1. You may wager any number of Benefit rolls. Roll Gambler 8+; if you fail, lose all the wagered Benefit rolls. If you succeed, gain half as many Benefit rolls as you wagered (round up). |
                    | 11 | A crime lord considers you his protégé. Either gain Tactics (military) 1 or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | You commit a legendary crime. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Scholar">
            <button text="Qualification">
                <markdown>
                    # Scholar
                    ---
                    Individuals trained in technological or research sciences who conduct scientific investigations into materials, situations and phenomena, or who practise medicine.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** INT 6+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Field Researcher:** You are an explorer or field researcher, equally at home in the laboratory or wilderness.
                    **Scientist:** You are a researcher in some corporation or research institution or a mad scientist in an orbiting laboratory.
                    **Physician:** You are a doctor, healer or medical researcher.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | Field Researcher | END 6+ | INT 6+ |
                    | Scientist | EDU 4+ | INT 8+ |
                    | Physician | EDU 4+ | EDU 8+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr5,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 2 | Cr10,000 | EDU +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr20,000 | Two Ship Shares |
                    | 4 | Cr30,000 | SOC +1 |
                    | 5 | CR40,000 | Scientific Equpiment |
                    | 6 | Cr60,000 | Lab Ship |
                    | 7 | Cr100,000 | Lab Ship |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 10) | Field Researcher | Scientist | Physician |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | INT +1 | Drive or Flyer | Art | Electronics | Admin | Medic |
                    | 2 | EDU +1 | Electronics | Advocate | Vacc Suit | Engineer | Electronics |
                    | 3 | SOC +1 | Diplomat | Electronics | Navigation | Science | Investigate |
                    | 4 | DEX +1 | Medic | Language | Survival | Science | Medic |
                    | 5 | END +1 | Investigate | Engineer | Investigate | Electronics | Persuade |
                    | 6 | Language | Science | Science | Science | Science | Science |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Field Researcher | Skill or Bonus | Scientist | Skill or Bonus | Physician | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 1 | — | Science 1 | — | Science 1 | — | Medic 1 |
                    | 2 | — | Electronics (computers) 1 | — | Electronics (computers) | — | — |
                    | 3 | — | Investigate 1 | — | Investigate 1 | — | Science 1 |
                    | 4 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                    | 5 | — | Science 2 | — | Science 2 | — | Science 2 |
                    | 6 | — | — | — | — | — | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | A disaster leaves several injured and others blame you, forcing you to leave your career. Roll on the Injury table twice, taking the higher result and gain a Rival. |
                    | 3 | The planetary government interferes with your research for political or religious reasons. If you continue with your work openly, increase Science by one level and gain an Enemy. If you continue with your work secretly, increase Science by one level and reduce your SOC by 2. This mishap does not cause you to leave this career. |
                    | 4 | An expedition or voyage goes wrong, leaving you stranded in the wilderness. Gain Survival 1 or Athletics (dexterity or endurance) 1. By the time you find your way home, your job is gone. |
                    | 5 | Your work is sabotaged by unknown parties. You may salvage what you can and give up (leave the career but retain this term’s Benefit roll) or start again from scratch (lose all Benefit rolls from this career but you do not have to leave). |
                    | 6 | A rival researcher blackens your name or steals your research. Gain a Rival but you do not have to leave this career. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | You are called upon to perform research that goes against your conscience. Accept and you gain an extra Benefit roll, a level in each of any two Science skill specialties and D3 Enemies. |
                    | 4 | You are assigned to work on a secret project for a patron or organisation. Gain one of Medic 1, Science 1, Engineer 1, Electronics 1 or Investigate 1. |
                    | 5 | You win a prestigious prize for your work, garnering both the praise and envy of your peers. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 6 | You are given advanced training in a specialist field. Roll EDU 8+ to gain any one skill of your choice at level 1. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | You have the opportunity to cheat in some fashion, advancing your career and research by stealing another’s work, using an alien device, taking a shortcut and so forth. If you refuse, you gain nothing. If you accept, roll Deception 8+ or Admin 8+. If you succeed, you gain DM+2 to any one Benefit roll and may increase any skill by one level but also gain an Enemy. If you fail, gain an Enemy and lose one Benefit roll from this career. |
                    | 9 | You make a breakthrough in your field. Gain DM+2 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 10 | You become entangled in a bureaucratic or legal morass that distracts you from your work. Gain one of Admin 1, Advocate 1, Persuade 1 or Diplomat 1. |
                    | 11 | You work for an eccentric but brilliant mentor, who becomes an Ally. Either increase Science by one level or DM+4 to your next advancement roll thanks to their aid. |
                    | 12 | Your work leads to a considerable breakthrough. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Scout ">
            <button text="Qualifiction">
                <markdown>
                    # Scout
                    ---
                    Members of the exploratory service. Scouts explore new areas, map and survey known or newly discovered areas and maintain communication ships which carry information and messages between the worlds of the galaxy.
                    ---
                    **Qualification:** INT 5+
                    DM-1 for every previous career
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Assignment">
                <markdown>
                    # Assignments
                    ---
                    Choose one of the following:
                    **Courier:** You are responsible for shuttling messages and high value packages around the galaxy.
                    **Surveyor:** You visit border worlds and assess their worth.
                    **Explorer:** You go wherever the map is blank, exploring unknown worlds and uncharted space.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Career Progress">
                <markdown>
                    # Career Progress
                    ---
                    | | Survival | Advancement |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | Courier | END 5+ | EDU 9+ |
                    | Surveyor | END 6+ | INT 8+ |
                    | Explorer | END 7+ | EDU 7+ |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mustering Out">
                <markdown>
                    # Mustering Out Benefits
                    ---
                    | 1D | Cash | Benefits|
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Cr20,000 | Ship Share |
                    | 2 | Cr20,000 | INT +1 |
                    | 3 | Cr30,000 | EDU +1 |
                    | 4 | Cr30,000 | Weapon |
                    | 5 | Cr50,000 | Weapon |
                    | 6 | Cr50,000 | Scout Ship |
                    | 7 | Cr50,000 | Scout Ship |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Skill Tables">
                <markdown>
                    # Skills and Training
                    ---
                    | 1D | Personal Development | Service Skills | Advanced Education (Min. EDU 8) | Courier | Surveyor | Explorer |
                    | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | STR +1 | Pilot (small craft or spacecraft) | Medic | Electronics | Electronics | Electronics |
                    | 2 | DEX +1 | Survival | Language | Flyer | Persuade | Pilot |
                    | 3 | END +1 | Mechanic | Seafarer | Pilot (spacecraft) | Pilot | Engineer |
                    | 4 | INT +1 | Astrogation | Explosives | Engineer | Navigation | Science |
                    | 5 | EDU +1 | Vacc Suit | Sicence | Athletics | Diplomat | Stealth |
                    | 6 | Jack-of-all-Trades | Gun Combat | Jack-of-all-Trades | Astrogation | Streetwise | Recon |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Ranks">
                <markdown>
                    # Ranks and Bonuses
                    ---
                    | Rank | Title | Skill or Bonus |
                    | --- | --- | --- |
                    | 0 | — | — |
                    | 1 | Scout | Vacc Suit 1 |
                    | 2 | — | — |
                    | 3 | Senior Scout | Pilot 1 |
                    | 4 | — | — |
                    | 5 | — | — |
                    | 6 | — | — |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Mishaps">
                <markdown>
                    # Mishaps
                    ---
                    | 1D | Mishap |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 1 | Severely injured (this is the same as a result of 2 on the Injury table). Alternatively, roll twice on the Injury table and take the lower result. |
                    | 2 | Psychologically damaged by your time in the scouts. Reduce your INT or SOC by 1. |
                    | 3 | Your ship is damaged and you have to hitch-hike your way back across the stars to the nearest scout base. Gain 1D Contacts and D3 Enemies. |
                    | 4 | You inadvertently cause a conflict between the Imperium and a minor world or species. Gain a Rival and Diplomat 1. |
                    | 5 | You have no idea what happened to you – they found your ship drifting on the fringes of friendly space. |
                    | 6 | Injured. Roll on the Injury table. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Events">
                <markdown>
                    # Events
                    ---
                    | 2D | Event |
                    | --- | --- |
                    | 2 | Disaster! Roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 3 | Your ship is ambushed by enemy vessels. Either run and roll Pilot 8+ to escape, or treat with them and roll Persuade 10+ to bargain with them. If you fail the check, then your ship is destroyed and you may not re-enlist in the Scouts at the end of this term. If you succeed, you survive and gain Electronics (sensors) 1. Either way, gain an Enemy. |
                    | 4 | You survey an alien world. Gain one of Animals (riding or training) 1, Survival 1, Recon 1 or Science 1. |
                    | 5 | You perform an exemplary service for the scouts. Gain DM+1 to any one Benefit roll. |
                    | 6 | You spend several years jumping from world to world in your scout ship. Gain one of Astrogation 1, Electronics 1, Navigation 1, Pilot (small craft) 1 or Mechanic 1. |
                    | 7 | Life Event. Roll on the Life Events table. |
                    | 8 | When dealing with an alien species , you have an opportunity to gather extra intelligence about them. Roll either Electronics 8+ or Deception 8+. If you succeed, gain an Ally in the Imperium and DM+2 to your next advancement roll. If you fail, roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 9 | Your scout ship is one of the first on the scene to rescue the survivors of a disaster. Roll either Medic 8+ or Engineer 8+. If you succeed, gain a Contact and DM+2 to your next advancement roll. If you fail, gain an Enemy. |
                    | 10 | You spend a great deal of time on the fringes of Charted Space. Roll Survival 8+ or Pilot 8+. If you succeed, gain a Contact in an alien species and one level in any skill of your choice. If you fail, roll on the Mishap table but you are not ejected from this career. |
                    | 11 | You serve as the courier for an important message from the Imperium. Either gain one level of Diplomat or DM+4 to your next advancement roll. |
                    | 12 | You discover a world, item or information of worth to the Imperium. You are automatically promoted. |
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
    </group>
    <group title="Skills Packages">
        <button text="Traveller">
            <markdown>
                # Traveller Skills Package
                ---
                This is an all-round skill package, good for a campaign where the Travellers are trading one week and blowing things up the next.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Deception 1, Electronics 1, Gun Combat 1, Gunner 1, Medic 1, Persuade 1, Pilot 1, Stealth 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Trader">
            <markdown>
                # Trader Skills Package
                ---
                This skills package is for campaigns where trading and commerce are the primary activities of the Travellers.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Advocate 1, Astrogation 1, Broker 1, Diplomat 1, Electronics 1, Medic 1, Pilot 1, Streetwise 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Explorer">
            <markdown>
                # Explorer Skills Package
                ---
                For campaigns where the Travellers are operating on the fringe of Charted Space, dealing with new worlds and ancient relics.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Astrogation 1, Electronics 1, Gun Combat 1, Medic 1, Pilot 1, Recon 1, Stealth 1, Survival 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Investigator">
            <markdown>
                # Investigator Skills Package
                ---
                For campaigns centring on solving crimes and investigating mysteries.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Admin 1, Advocate 1, Deception 1, Electronics 1, Gun Combat 1, Investigate 1, Persuade 1, Stealth 1, Streetwise 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Mercenary">
            <markdown>
                # Mercenary Skills Package
                ---
                This skills package focuses on ground combat and is aimed at combat-heavy games.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Electronics 1, Medic 1, Leadership 1, Heavy Weapons 1, Gun Combat 1, Gun Combat 1, Stealth 1, Recon 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Starship">
            <markdown>
                # Starship Skills Package
                ---
                This is for campaigns where the Travellers will spend almost all their time on spacecraft.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Astrogation 1, Electronics 1, Engineer 1, Gunner 1, Mechanic 1, Medic 1, Pilot 1, Tactics (naval) 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Diplomat">
            <markdown>
                # Diplomat Skills Package
                ---
                For campaigns where the Travellers are government operatives and ambassadors.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Admin 1, Advocate 1, Deception 1, Diplomat 1, Electronics 1, Persuade 1, Stealth 1, Streetwise 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Criminal">
            <markdown>
                # Criminal Skills Package
                ---
                For campaigns involving crime and elaborate heists.
                ---
                **Skills:**
                Broker 1, Deception 1, Electronics 1, Medic 1, Persuade 1, Pilot 1, Stealth 1, Streetwise 1
            </markdown>
        </button>
    </group>
    <group title="Skills">
        <button text="Admin">
            <markdown>
                # Admin
                ---
                This skill covers bureaucracies and administration of all sorts, including the navigation of bureaucratic obstacles or disasters. It also covers tracking inventories, ship manifests and other records.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <button text="Advocate">
            <markdown>
                # Advocate
                ---
                Advocate gives a knowledge of common legal codes and practises, especially interstellar law. It also gives the Traveller experience in oratory, debate and public speaking, making it an excellent skill for lawyers and politicians.
            </markdown>
        </button>
        <subgroup title="Animals">
            <button text="Animals">
                <markdown>
                    # Animals
                    ---
                    This skill, rare on industrialised or technologically advanced worlds, is for the care of animals.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Handling">
                <markdown>
                    # Animals (handling)
                    ---
                    The Traveller knows how to handle an animal and ride those trained to bear a rider. Unusual animals raise the difficulty of the check.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Veterinary">
                <markdown>
                    # Animals (veterinary)
                    ---
                    The Traveller is trained in veterinary medicine and animal care.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Training">
                <markdown>
                    The Traveller knows how to tame and train animals.
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
        <subgroup title="Art">
            <button text="Art">
                <markdown>
                    # Art
                    ---
                    The Traveller is trained in a type of creative art.
                </markdown>
            </button>
            <button text="Performer">
                <markdown>
                    # Performer
                    ---
                    The Traveller is a trained actor, dancer or singer at home on the stage, screen or holo.
                </markdown>
            </button>
        </subgroup>
    </group>
</control_panel>